Kendra Morris

Frisco, Texas • kendranmorris@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/kendra-morris • https://moonlit-mermaid-59cc47.netlify.app/

Full Stack Developer

Fullstack Developer with over a decade of experience in healthcare, prior experience with marketing, and a growing curiosity for software development! I have an interest in complex problem-solving, and have a strong analytical mindset. I am actively seeking a role that fosters continuous growth and innovation!

EDUCATION

Full Stack Software Development

University Of Texas Dallas • Oct 2023

Masters of Science in Kinesiology

University of North Texas • Denton, TX • Aug 2020 - May 2022

Bachelors of Science in Exercise Science

University of North Carolina at Charlotte • Charlotte, NC • Aug 2015 - May 2019

CERTIFICATIONS

Fullstack Software Development

University of Texas Dallas • May 2023 - Oct 2023

PROJECTS

Girl Dinner

Sep 2023 - Oct 2023

https://github.com/kmorr102/Girl-Dinner

- Designed a review site for users to review and interact with local restaurants
- · Leveraged the power of PostgreSQL to create a robust backend system that seamlessly integrated with our frontend website
- Designed and implemented a RESTful API using PostgreSQL as the database management system
- Created endpoints and utilized test automation and debugging with insomnia that enabled users to perform essential CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations on the data
- Collaborated within a cross-functional Agile Environment team throughout the entirety of the project
- Documented all active and completed task on a weekly basis using a project board

Stranger's Things

Aug 2023 - Aug 2023

https://github.com/kmorr102/strangers-things

- Designed and implemented a user-friendly website facilitating seamless transactions for buying and selling personal items
- Utilized React, React Toastify, CSS, and HTML to create an intuitive, visually appealing interface
- Implemented authentication and security by incorporating JWTs, enhancing user data protection
- · Employed Insomnia for thorough API testing and validation

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intuitive Health: Legacy ER and Urgent Care • Frisco, TX • Full-time • Sep 2022 - Present

Lab Coordinator

- Streamline lab operations by coordinating equipment maintenance and inventory to meet fluctuating patient demands within budget.
- Manages proficiency testing for 15 employees, resulting in improved reporting accuracy and identification of training needs.
- Implements quality control standards and improved overall accuracy of manual lab test to 98%
- · Completion of monthly deliverables

Emergency Room Technician

- Maintains a high level of patient satisfaction through comprehensive care under physician orders in a fast paced environment
- · Increases patient satisfaction scores through timely treatment, and decreased door to door times below 60 minutes
- · Reduces documentation errors by 10% through thorough documentation of patient encounters with the EMR system
- Use of language interpretation tools like video remote interpretation(VRI) and over the phone interpretation (OPI)

Acadian Ambulance • Dallas, Texas, USA • Dec 2020 - Sep 2022

Emergency Medical Technician

- Performed basic life support while documenting all aspects of pre-hospital patient encounter, resulting in efficient and accurate patient care.
- Conducted efficient patient interviews utilizing electronic medical record systems, ensuring accurate medical history and complaint documentation
- Maintained professionalism while communicating with medical providers, patients, and family members, resulting in improved customer experience and a foundational role in a growing team.

University of North Texas: Recreation Sports • Denton, TX • Aug 2020 - May 2022

Fitness Graduate Assistant

- Designed effective marketing strategies that resulted in 20% increase in student engagement with the use of social media marketing, video marketing as well as email marketing.
- Supervised 65+ student staff, maximizing facility operations and elevating patron satisfaction
- Implemented data analytic strategies to increase program engagement, resulting in more efficient use of resources and improved program planning initiatives.
- Acted as a mentor to prospective personal trainer and group fitness students
- Collaborated with marketing teams to maintain social media presence through content management and marketing components.
- Analyzed patron participant data and designed charts, graphs, and other illustrations to present program success and promote future program planning

SKILLS & INTERESTS

DIY Crafts, Dog Training, Furniture Flipping, Travel

Technical Skills: API, coding, Database Design, Express.js, Github, HTML/CSS, Insomnia, Javascript, JSON, Node.js, Postbird, PostgreSQL, Software Development Life Cycle, SQL, Visual Studio Code

Soft Skills: Attention To Detail, Collaboration, communication skills, context switching, Energetic, Interpersonal Skills, Leadership, Organized, planning, Quick Learner, Self-starter, Teamwork, Time management, troubleshooting, verbal communication skills